<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://tifflabs.org/</id><title>tiff labs</title><subtitle>A blog about smart homes made with Home Assistant and home labs.</subtitle> <updated>2024-05-25T23:02:21-04:00</updated> <author> <name>tiff</name> <uri>https://tifflabs.org/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://tifflabs.org/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="https://tifflabs.org/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2024 tiff </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Heads Up</title><link href="https://tifflabs.org/posts/heads-up/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Heads Up" /><published>2024-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</published> <updated>2024-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated> <id>https://tifflabs.org/posts/heads-up/</id> <content src="https://tifflabs.org/posts/heads-up/" /> <author> <name>tiff</name> </author> <summary> I am still around! I am working on a loadout post for a Toolsday entry I started on literally this past Tuesday but taking and editing the photos has taken some time. I’ve also started using Amazon Affiliate Links, which you can find the disclosure about on the tab sidebar. I use non-invasive analytics with GoatCounter. However I have no issue with you blocking any analytics or affiliate l... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Toolsday</title><link href="https://tifflabs.org/posts/toolsday-posts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Toolsday" /><published>2024-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</published> <updated>2024-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated> <id>https://tifflabs.org/posts/toolsday-posts/</id> <content src="https://tifflabs.org/posts/toolsday-posts/" /> <author> <name>tiff</name> </author> <category term="DIY" /> <category term="Toolsday" /> <summary> I am a big time sucker for gadgets of all types and that includes power and manual tools. Every Tuesday1 will be Toolsday where I highlight a particular YouTube channel, tool, or tool haul2 on the blog. Sometimes I may even do a demonstration or review of a tool I’ve had or picked up recently. I love tools and I’ve been going balls deep into Tool and DIY YouTube these past two months. Toolsda... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Moving Proxmox to New Subnet</title><link href="https://tifflabs.org/posts/moving-proxmox/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moving Proxmox to New Subnet" /><published>2024-04-05T22:40:00-04:00</published> <updated>2024-04-05T22:40:00-04:00</updated> <id>https://tifflabs.org/posts/moving-proxmox/</id> <content src="https://tifflabs.org/posts/moving-proxmox/" /> <author> <name>tiff</name> </author> <category term="Homelab" /> <category term="Proxmox" /> <summary> I’ve been wanting to get my Proxmox cluster plugged into my UDM Pro for at least a year now. A few issues were: Accessing the cluster from a different subnet Updating the IP address of each node in the cluster Keeping old LXC containers and VMs in tact Keeping HDD and SSD mountpoints in tact Wait. Why? You may be asking, “tiff, why move the cluster at all?” This is a fair thing to ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>State of the Lab: 2024</title><link href="https://tifflabs.org/posts/state-of-the-lab/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="State of the Lab: 2024" /><published>2024-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2024-04-17T00:44:54-04:00</updated> <id>https://tifflabs.org/posts/state-of-the-lab/</id> <content src="https://tifflabs.org/posts/state-of-the-lab/" /> <author> <name>tiff</name> </author> <category term="Homelab" /> <summary> It’s been a almost two years since I shredded my quad and was bedridden for all of 2022 up until May of 2023. Would have spent the whole of 2023 on the streets if not for close friends and family who allowed me to setup my gear in the small room I am in now. I have managed to increase the amount of services running because of Proxmox VE Helper Scripts while learning more of the homelab ropes ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Building a Home Lab, Pt. 1</title><link href="https://tifflabs.org/posts/building-a-home-lab-pt.-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a Home Lab, Pt. 1" /><published>2023-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2024-04-17T00:44:54-04:00</updated> <id>https://tifflabs.org/posts/building-a-home-lab-pt.-1/</id> <content src="https://tifflabs.org/posts/building-a-home-lab-pt.-1/" /> <author> <name>tiff</name> </author> <category term="Homelab" /> <summary> I’ve had one going for a while but today, it’s cleanup day. Some background… Home Assistant got me into DevOps. Don’t get me wrong, I was interested, but the more I read about Home Assistant and tinkered with it, the more When SysAdmins Ruled the Earth made sense1. So I went all in with my first rack, an Aeons 9U rack from Amazon… My friend had never done something like this, and while ... </summary> </entry> </feed>
