<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://tifflabs.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://tifflabs.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-12-01T20:16:55-05:00</updated><id>https://tifflabs.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">tiff labs</title><subtitle>A blog about smart homes made with Home Assistant and home labs.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Building a Home Lab, Pt. 1</title><link href="https://tifflabs.org/posts/building-a-home-lab-pt.-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a Home Lab, Pt. 1" /><published>2023-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://tifflabs.org/posts/building-a-home-lab-pt.-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tifflabs.org/posts/building-a-home-lab-pt.-1/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve had one going for a while but today, it’s cleanup day.</p>

<h2 id="background">Background</h2>

<p>Home Assistant got me into DevOps.</p>

<p>Don’t get me wrong, I was interested, but the more I read about Home Assistant and tinkered with it, the more <em><a href="https://www.feedbooks.com/book/335/when-sysadmins-ruled-the-earth">When SysAdmins Ruled the Earth</a></em> made sense<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>So I went all in with my first rack, an Aeons 9U rack from Amazon…</p>

<p><img src="tifflabs/image/upload/v1699686150/r-with-9u-rack.jpg" alt="" />
<em>My friend had never done something like this, and while he’s handy, I am a better DIY’er for sure</em></p>

<p><img src="tifflabs/image/upload/v1699686149/r-finishes-9u-rack.jpg" alt="" />
<em>R putting the finishing touches on the rack</em></p>

<p><img src="tifflabs/image/upload/v1699686150/9u-rack-final.jpg" alt="" />
<em>The finished rack</em></p>

<p>The cable management inside the cabinet is… <em>rough</em>. But it was my first cabinet.</p>

<p>This was at my old old place, a 2br apartment in the suburbs where I live.</p>

<h2 id="open-or-closed-cabinet-who-knows">Open or closed cabinet? Who knows…</h2>

<p>I wasn’t happy with the rack being so low off the ground; I am really tall, and sitting in my office chair trying to fix things in the cabinet was tedious. Sure, I <em>could</em> squat and do it, but I am old and my knees hurt. There was no way that was going to happen, hence my friend R putting the cabinet together<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>.</p>

<p>I decided to pick up an Echogear rack, 15U, where everything would be easy to fix and modify. But as you can see, the cables are… well, still bad.</p>

<p><img src="tifflabs/image/upload/v1699686150/blue-lab-old-place.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Closer look at the lab area of my old office</em></p>

<p><img src="tifflabs/image/upload/v1699686150/full-blue-lab.jpg" alt="" />
<em>The whole office, in blue</em></p>

<h3 id="the-worst">The worst</h3>

<p>Since I spun up that lab, life has gotten significantly worse, for me and for everyone in my industry. Inflation rising means there’s less VC cash being invested and burned on stupid novelties from small startups, and layoffs continue to happen. I was one of the unlucky ones.</p>

<p>It was bad because I’d just moved to a townhouse, hoping to have a garage lab, but the morning after I moved, after just 6 hours sleep, I shredded my quad being old and trying to get up from a very low position in an awkward way.</p>

<p>So now, I have a house, I am still working, but I cannot walk. At work we get another round of funding but the market is drying up for our product and the suits are skittish. The funding round was good but it wasn’t enough to keep everyone, and there were only three proper employees, the rest of the team were contractors. This meant, the software engineer that worked on the least important product (that was me), got the pink slip. My boss left too, it was hard, but I got through it.</p>

<p>This meant, however, that I’d need to rely on my savings and investments. It helped but my runway ran out, too, so I had to move again, and with inflation the way it is, I am now couch surfing with old family friends. Stuff happens, but I am in a warm, safe, place and can finally walk without limping.</p>

<h2 id="in-a-room">In a room</h2>

<p>My roommate allowed me to bring most of my gear along. I hastily threw it all together and it looks like it.</p>

<p><img src="tifflabs/image/upload/c_scale,w_1244/v1700171631/messy-rack_a1hkyg.jpg" alt="" />
<em>This is an absolute <strong>abomination</strong></em></p>

<p>But I’ve found the resolve to fix it, even though I am expecting to get my own place in the near future<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>.</p>

<h3 id="stripping-cutting-and-putting-headers-on-ethernet-cables">Stripping, cutting, and putting headers on ethernet cables</h3>

<p>Step one, before I even tear this thing down, is to make sure I have the appropriate length for each component’s ethernet cable. As you can see, the runs are all kind of different lengths and colors which makes it not only unappealing to look at but a PITA to fix things. Nothing is labled, different colors for different types of devices where things of different types should be grouped. NUCs not put in racks just on top of other NUCs and not labeled. Raspberry Pis dangling. And the whole rack is ass backwards so the switches are hard to reach. There are power bricks daisy chained on the CyberPower power strip and I don’t want that at all.</p>

<p>Several power bricks have different lengths and some of the bricks take up two or three outlets, meaning I need to daisy chain and add more and more power bricks. It isn’t ideal at all and I need to fix it. Pronto.</p>

<h3 id="tools-of-the-trade">Tools of the trade</h3>

<p>I bought an ethernet cutter/stripper kit to work with the cables. I will be purchasing a few spools of different colored cables and documenting which devices get which colors and what ports they are plugged into with Bookstack, my network documentation tool of choice.</p>

<p>(There’s a video on Bookstack coming soon. I’ll link it here once I finish editing it.)</p>

<p><img src="tifflabs/image/upload/c_scale,w_1862/v1700171632/top-tools_a3rk6e.jpg" alt="" />
<em>The stuff I’ve accumlated over the past 8 years is wild. Thanks Adafruit!</em></p>

<h2 id="and-more-projects">And more projects…</h2>

<p>I have a whole host of Arduino and ESPHome boards I am going to be using to enhance my smart home<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>.</p>

<p>I am excited to:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Clean up the rack</li>
  <li>Build cool stuff</li>
  <li>Move to my own place(!!!)</li>
  <li>Get my life back</li>
</ol>

<p>One day at a time. One day at a time.</p>

<!-- ![](tifflabs/image/upload/c_scale,w_1862/v1700171632/toolsday_pt68mn.jpg) -->

<p><img src="tifflabs/image/upload/q_75/v1699686151/old-fridge-of-cold-ones.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Always need a fridge full of fizzy water</em></p>

<blockquote class="prompt-info">
  <p>Except where otherwise noted, the blog posts on this site are licensed
under the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NonDeriv 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-ND BY 4.0) License by the author.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="tifflabs/image/upload/v1700006329/CC_BY-NC-ND_mpmqvt.svg" alt="" width="120" /></p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>At least to me. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>We also did a terrible job and installing the components, making this setup more difficult to work with than it needed to be. <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Even though I bought a 12U cabinet earlier this year, this is an eyesore and needs to be cleaned up. <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Because I am just in one room, the only thing I will do here is test each DIY device I build; the smarts don’t need to happen right now. <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>tiff</name></author><category term="Home Lab" /><category term="meta" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Revitalizing a hot mess of cables]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Migrating Devices to Separate Networks</title><link href="https://tifflabs.org/posts/migrating-devices-separate-networks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrating Devices to Separate Networks" /><published>2023-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://tifflabs.org/posts/migrating-devices-separate-networks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tifflabs.org/posts/migrating-devices-separate-networks/"><![CDATA[<p>With my new UniFi Ap up and running, I plan on migrating my cameras to different networks I created in the UniFi controller.</p>

<p>I am still learning about how to use a VLAN and how to set one up on my Ap.</p>

<p>So far, I’ve got a nice overview of traffic coming through my network.</p>

<p>I’ll be writing more soon.</p>

<p><img src="twhiteblog/image/upload/v1692760963/network_sxovp3.webp" alt="" /></p>]]></content><author><name>tiff</name></author><category term="Networking" /><category term="meta" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[VLANs are one way to separate IoT devices from your main network]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Curiosity and Home Assistant</title><link href="https://tifflabs.org/posts/curiosity-and-home-assistant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Curiosity and Home Assistant" /><published>2023-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T01:20:38-05:00</updated><id>https://tifflabs.org/posts/curiosity-and-home-assistant</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tifflabs.org/posts/curiosity-and-home-assistant/"><![CDATA[<p>A brief post here.</p>

<p>Getting into Home Assistant has been the best thing to happen to me in a long time. It has not only been fun, but as a software engineer by trade, it has made me better at my job and understanding the pipes that gird all the infrastructure I build apps on top of.</p>

<p>It’s taken me a little under two years to feel comfortable with terms like:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Proxmox</li>
  <li>NGINX</li>
  <li>NGINX Proxy Manager</li>
  <li>Docker</li>
  <li>Portainter</li>
  <li>VMs</li>
  <li>Bittorrent</li>
  <li>How to tunnel traffic securely by using Cloudflare and NPM to and from Home Assistant</li>
</ul>

<p>and more.</p>

<p>These were terms I’d heard of but never understood and was too scared to find out more about.</p>

<p>Now I have a small home lab and switches everywhere.</p>

<p>I am neurodivergent and these past three years have been incredibly difficult for me. Diving into Home Assistant, DevOps, and building apps has literally saved my life more times than I can count.</p>

<h2 id="welp">Welp</h2>

<p>That got a bit mushy at the end there innit.</p>

<p>But it’s true. And at the end of the day, it’s <em>fun</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name>tiff</name></author><category term="Home Assistant" /><category term="meta" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A brief post here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Slow and Dirty Dashboards</title><link href="https://tifflabs.org/posts/slow-and-dirty-dashboards/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Slow and Dirty Dashboards" /><published>2023-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-08-15T06:11:36-04:00</updated><id>https://tifflabs.org/posts/slow-and-dirty-dashboards</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tifflabs.org/posts/slow-and-dirty-dashboards/"><![CDATA[<blockquote class="prompt-info">
  <p>It’s been a minute, hasn’t it? I was busy at work, the startup life continuing to cause burnout for me, and the following tech crash meant that I would not be working for a few months as I tried to pick up the pieces of what remained of my work and move forward.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The recession has hit us all hard, some more than others, as 10s of thousands of tech workers have been laid off. I feel lucky that I don’t feel like I’ll be on the market for long and that I can finally create the content I want across my entire suite of blogs and YouTube channels.</p>

<p>Now, on with the article.</p>

<p>I have recently been down a large rabbit hole with my favorite home automation software, <a href="https://home-assistant.io">Home Assistant</a>. You can expose as much or as little of your smart home to the wider internet or move everything off the cloud and keep your devices local behind a firewall and separated from your main network and a VLAN.</p>

<p>I’m not interested in ligating this at the moment; what I want to write about <em>today</em> is Home Assistant dashboards.</p>

<h2 id="what-are-dashboards">What are dashboards?</h2>
<p>Dashboards are just that; a place where you can collect different aspects of your Home Assistant instance using Lovelace cards that display that information in a visual way.</p>

<p>I am trying to figure out who my audience is for this blog so please keep that in mind while reading this. If this is too basic for you, <a href="mailto:contact@suburbansmarts.org">reach out to me</a> so that I can understand what you want to read, what you don’t, and your skill level and I’ll adjust these articles based on that feedback.</p>

<h2 id="can-you-please-just-show-me-examples">Can you please just show me examples??</h2>

<p>Sure! Here are a few of my dashboards in Home Assistant below.</p>

<h2 id="have-an-interesting-dashboard">Have an interesting dashboard?</h2>

<p>I’d like to hear from you! You can send me your dashboards at <a href="mailto:dashboards@suburbansmarts.org">dashboards at Suburban Smarts dot org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks!</p>]]></content><author><name>tiff</name></author><category term="Home Assistant" /><category term="dashboard" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a minute, hasn’t it? I was busy at work, the startup life continuing to cause burnout for me, and the following tech crash meant that I would not be working for a few months as I tried to pick up the pieces of what remained of my work and move forward.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Content update, Vine Voice edition</title><link href="https://tifflabs.org/posts/content-update-vine-voice-edition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Content update, Vine Voice edition" /><published>2022-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T01:19:29-05:00</updated><id>https://tifflabs.org/posts/content-update-vine-voice-edition</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tifflabs.org/posts/content-update-vine-voice-edition/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been working on content  verticals for Suburban Smarts; things like writing reviews of smart home products, engaging in the Home Assistant community on Facebook<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> and pumping out more content on this website and soon, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@tifflabs">YouTube</a><sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>.</p>

<p>This is beginning to pay off for me in a big way:</p>

<p>I’ve been invited to an Amazon program that I can’t remember if I can disclose here or not<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> but I can tell you it’ll make me want to create more content, right here on this blog.</p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Trying to up my game in the forums, too. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>And failing <em>horribly</em>. <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>I’ll need to reread the <em>fine print</em>. <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>tiff</name></author><category term="Updates" /><category term="meta" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing reviews for Amazon Vine for YOU.]]></summary></entry></feed>